Okay, so in this video then, we are going
to cover the PIMBOC guide processes of
cost management as relates to PIMBOC
version 6.
Okay, so in PIMBOC, under this section,
cost management, there are four processes.
These are the four processes, they fall
under planning and monitoring controlling.
Now the very first
process then that PMI talks
about is something called
plan cost management.
and just like any of the knowledge areas,
right, so if you look at the process grid,
if you look at the process map,
right, the very first process in planning
is always going to be plan
something management,
right, and that's something
being the knowledge area.
So in this case then, cost management is a
knowledge area.
So the first process then is plan cost
management.
And the artifact that we're creating,
the document that we're creating,
right, in plan.
cost management or in this process called
plan cost management, right?
For PMI's purposes or for PIMBOC guide
purposes, they're known as outputs.
So the output that we're creating is
something called the cost management plan.
The cost management plan is a document,
a very important document.
It's an artifact.
Right.
So again, any artifact is a document that
you are creating.
And in the old PIMBOC six terminology,
they used to call it output.
It was an output of plan cost management.
And there's a separate
video on the cost management
plan, and any management
plan is documenting procedures.
So the cost management plan is documenting
how we're going to estimate the cost and
come up with the budget and so and so
forth.
Like said, separate video on that
altogether.
Then the next process under planning is
this one called estimate cost.
And estimate cost refers to estimating the
costs of individual activities,
individual components of the project,
right?
Or individual work packages.
So before you can come up with the overall
budget for the project, we need to know
how much each individual component is
going to cost.
And then we're going to add those up to
come up with the overall budget.
And that's what the estimate cost process
refers to, right?
It's coming up with a cost of individual
activities.
And in fact, the output
of estimate cost, the old
pinbox six output was
the activity cost estimate.
And then the other process and the next
process is determined budget.
So once we have estimated
the cost of individual activities,
now we can come up with the
overall budget for the project.
And that's what that determined budget.
We first have to figure out cost of
individuals, then aggregate those,
add those up to come up with the overall
budget.
For PMI's purposes, the project manager's
budget is known as the cost budget.
baseline.
So it was a cost baseline that is considered
as the output of determined budget.
And the cost baseline obviously is an
artifact.
It's an important artifact.
And it's considered as the output of
determined budget.
And again, separate video on those as
well.
I had separate videos on cost aggregation,
right, which is the tool and technique of
estimate cost, and then
separate video on cost baseline,
which is considered an
output of determined budget.
And the cost baseline is a project
manager's budget that includes contingency
reserves, right, does not include
management reserves.
So contingency reserves
are for known risks,
the responsibility of the project manager.
Management reserves are for complete
unknowns responsibility of senior management.
Project manager is not responsible for
management reserves.
They're responsible for contingency
reserves.
Contingency reserves are
included in the cost baseline,
which is basically an
output of determined budget.
So these are the planning processes.
In monitoring controlling, then,
the process is called control costs.
And remember, what is monitoring and
controlling?
Overall, what is monitoring controlling?
You are comparing actual results from
executing with your plan.
That is monitoring controlling.
Right.
So if you're comparing actual results with
your plan, and we're talking about cost
management, essentially it's referring to,
are we over budget or under budget?
How much money is left to spend on the
project?
How much over budget or under budget are
we going to be by the end of the project?
What cost performance have we been working
at?
What cost performance do
we need to achieve in order
to meet our original
budget and so and so forth?
So these are all the
earned value formulas that
we are going to be
covering in a separate slide.
In fact, there's several separate slides
where we are going to be covering these
earned value formulas and these earned
value terms.
But all of those earned value formulas
falls under this process here and this
process group called monitoring
controlling.
And the process is control cost.
We are monitoring controlling our cost.
This is what we should have spent.
That's planning.
This is the estimate cost of individual
activities.
and the overall budget for the project.
This is what we should have spent.
Executing is this is what we actually
spent.
So you're comparing your actual results
with your plan.
And then the difference is how much over
budget or under budget
and so and so forth.
So all of the different
formulas we're going to
be covering in the own
value management videos.
Now, you might be asking, well,
if we're comparing our plan with our
actual results in execute, how come
there's no boxes in execute?
Why is there no processes in executing?
Well, a simple reason is because the
executing process, remember from previous
video, the executing process is
direct-and-managed project work.
The very first process
in the process grid under
executing is called
direct-in-managed project work.
That's where we get the actual results
from.
So these are the old PIMBox 6 processes
that make up part of PMI standards.
Still relevant, although
we call them old, they
are still relevant for
the current PNP exam.